Rahul Hareendran

Product Designer & User Experience Architect

Experience

HFA DeFi Research

Nov 2023 → Present Nov 2022 → March 2023

El Cerrito, CA / Remote

Kloudspot

March 2023 → Nov 2023 Bangalore, India

MetroBank, UK

July 2021 → Oct 2022 London, United Kingdom

ila Bank

Dec 2019 → June 2021 Manama, Bahrain

DH Anticounterfeit

May 2018 → Dec 2019 Halmstad, Sweden

Consulting

May 2017 → Apr 2018 Bangalore, India

BigBinary

Aug 2014 → May 2017 Miami, FL / Remote

Bang the Table (Granicus)

May 2010 → July 2014 Melbourne, Australia / Remote

Beehively

Aug 2008 → Apr 2010 Ahmedabad, India

Product Design Consultant

 Designed UX for <u>HFA Research</u>'s DeFi dashboard to <u>visualize blockchain</u> <u>ecosystem transactions</u> and money flow, used by 500+ (paid subscribers) Web3 analysts and investors.

Principal Product Design Consultant

- Designed UX for our <u>predictive analytics platform</u> to help airports and public spaces optimise operations and manage crowd.
- Designed a scalable and maintainable <u>space design framework</u> for our <u>digital transformation suite</u>.

Principal Product Design Consultant

- Designed UX for commercial banking, reduced support call volumes by 17%, rectifying major customer pain points by redesigning key user journeys and information architecture.
- Improved business origination and customer onboarding decline rate by 21% by enhancing onboarding user experience.

Principal User Experience Architect

- Established design processes and guided a design team of 8 designers, liaised with 5+ design agencies and creators.
- Implemented the UX process for ila Bank's digital banking platform
- Created <u>delightful experiences</u> that won 10+ awards including Red Dot Award, Global Finance Middle East's Best UX Design, Seamless' Best Banking Experience award, and Transform MEA award.
- Implemented UX for a fully digital onboarding in less than 5 mins.

User Experience Architect

- Created UX for <u>CaseMate, for brand protection</u> used by 60+ clients such as Daimler, Volkswagen, PVH, Sony & Superdry.
- Built the insights engine and increased website take-downs by 40% and marketplace listing take-downs by 34%

Lead Product Designer

- Built UX and UI for <u>ICICI Bank's banking app</u>. Improved the app store ratings to 4.6/5 from 4.1/5 in 3 months of launch.
- Overhauled UX and UI for <u>HDFC Bank car loans</u>, decreasing the drop-off/ abandonment rate by 9%

Lead Product Designer

- Implemented UX, and UI for the compliance manager solution, <u>AAPC</u>
 Healthicity involving 10 key tools for compliance.
- Implemented UI and Front-end for <u>UL Solutions' Markshub</u>, <u>UL Go</u>, and <u>UL Verify</u>, servicing more than 1,500 standards.

Lead UI/UX & Front-end Designer

- Designed UX, UI for EngagementHQ which increased engagement by 28% across tools like Q&A, forums and surveys.
- Implemented a <u>front-end branding framework</u>.

UI/UX & Front-end Designer

 Designed UI/UX and Front-end framework for school management software, <u>Beehively</u> connecting parents, teachers, and students of 100+ public and private schools in the U.S. rahulmax@gmail.com +91 968 6699 669 linkedin.com/in/rahulmax rahulmax.com

Skills

About

Product designer and User Experience Architect with 15+ years' experience. Process involves lean UX design practices based on user centric design, focused on my clients' business goals and the user needs.

Hard Skills

Product Design, User Experience Research, Product Strategy, Competitor Analysis, Strategic Planning, Stakeholder Interviews, User Interface Design, Interaction Design, Information Architecture, Design Systems Management, Wireframing, Rapid Prototyping, Usability Testing, A/B Testing, User Interviews, Thematic Analysis, User Journey Mapping, Heuristic Analysis, Contextual Inquiries, Analytics Review, Agile Methodologies.

Tech Skills

Figma, Sketch, Miro, Invision, Maze, Google Analytics, PowerBI, Lookback, UserTesting, Mouseflow, Userpilot, UXCam.

Education

B Tech - Computer Science

Government Engineering College, Thrissur, India

Human-Computer Interaction, UC San Diego

Coursera, Online